Duc (David) Le

Full Stack Engineer

6	wa.me/+84973877428
\square	ducqhle@gmail.com
in	linkedin.com/in/ducqhle
0	ducqhle.github.io

Summary

With about 5 years of experience, I've developed highly interactive applications using the latest web technologies. I've contributed to 5+ projects with SEO optimization, high interactive UX/UI, performance, and full responsive. I took pride in both getting the task done and constantly seeking ways to make it better. I'm a lifelong learner with a problem-solving mindset, always striving for excellence.

Work experience

Full Stack Engineer

2021-01 - present

Spiderbox Design

- Developed fully responsive UIs for various applications, leveraging cutting-edge technologies including ReactJS, TypeScript, NextJS, Formik, Yup, React Emotion, Material-UI, and .NET Core.
- The work involved writing high-quality code, continuously refactoring it, and adding unit tests to ensure its integrity.
- Actively contributed to code reviews and provided support to multiple teams, fostering collaboration and maintaining coding standards.
- Adapted swiftly to new technologies, I seamlessly handled diverse requirements, such as React Native, D3JS, MJML, VueJS, and PowerBI.
- Delved into complex front-end issues, utilizing my deep codebase knowledge and library API specifications like Ag-grid, MobX, and upgraded Material-UI versions.
- Collaborated in creating and managing the ReactJS internship program, establishing schedules and agendas while skillfully onboarding and mentoring new team members.
- Collaborated with the Australia team on a daily basis.

Software Engineer

2020-07 - 2021-01

Ubitec

- Made significant contributions to the development and maintenance of the bot-platform.
- The work evolved working with ReactJS, NodeJS, TypeScript, Microsoft Bot Framework, React Flow, and Redux to enhance and maintain the core features of the platform.
- Conducted thorough research to ensure the successful implementation of chatbot application requirements and system.
- Added new code and maintaining code coverage, ensured the robustness and reliability of the platform, also diligently performed unit tests using Jest, React Testing Library, and Fast Check.
- Played a key role in configured the CI/CD process, utilizing Jenkins and Docker, and integrating them with Bitbucket and OpenShift.

Software Engineer

2018-09 - 2020-04

KMS Technology, Inc

- Developed end-to-end features, investigated issues full flow from back-end (.NET, NodeJS), database (MSQL) to front-end (ASP.NET).
- Migrated a .NET legacy system from monolith to cloud base service by using AWS Lambda, .NET core and NodeJS.
- Built a AI chatbot assistant powered by Microsoft Cognitive Services and Microsoft Bot Framework to help administration team supporting employees with the knowledge base building around the FAQ documents.

Education

Bachelor's degree, Technology Information

2015-09 - 2018-06

University of Science

Certifications

- NodeJS Certificate of Completion Learn and Understand NodeJS Udemy
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux) Udemy
- The Complete Guide to Advanced React Component Patterns Udemy
- KMS Techcon Certificate of Appreciation

Volenteering

- 2017 Participated YouthSpeak Performance Charity Non-profit organization that provides performance opportunities for young people, focusing on issues such as social justice, mental health, and education
- 2018 Participated in Germer Non-profit organization with a mission to bring classical music closer to Vietnamese people.
- 2019 Participated in an activity combining marathon running and cleaning up trash at Can Gio beach., organized by KMS.